Guida West Papers, 1946-2006
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES VII. SPEECHES AND TESTIMONY
  - "The Political Aging of Welfare Rights Women Leaders," Research Today and Tomorrow: A Multidisciplinary Conference on Women, Culture and Aging, 7 Apr 1984 (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - "The Political Aging of Welfare Rights Women Leaders," NJ Research Conference on Women, Rutgers, 22 May 1984 (Box 49)
    - Drafts and notes (Box 49, Folder 17)
    - Typescript with comments for rewrite (Box 49, Folder 18)
  - "Politics and Economics: Career Paths of Women Leaders in the Welfare Rights Movement," Nat'l Women's Studies Assn Annual Conference, 25 Jun 1984 (Box 49)
    - Typescript (Box 49, Folder 19)
    - Notes and drafts (Box 49, Folder 20)
    - Revised versions, Sep-Oct 1984 (Box 49, Folder 21)
  - "Religion and Protest: An Analysis of Welfare Rights Women Leaders," NJ Research Conference on Women, 21 May 1985 (Box 49)
    - Typescripts (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, drafts, and notes (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Testimony at Essex County Courthouse on the effectiveness of child support enforcement in general and in New Jersey, 20 Jul 1985 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Keynote at 19th Annual Welfare Rights Conference, Ohio State Welfare Rights Organization, 28 Jun 1985 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - "National Welfare Rights Leaders One Decade Later: Gender, Race and Class Analysis" (aka "Profiles of Protest of NWRO Leaders: One Decade Later, A Gender, Race and Class Analysis"), American Sociological Association, 30 Aug 1985 (Box 50)
    - Typescripts (Box 50)
      - Pre-conference version with reviewers' notes, Jan-Feb (Box 50, Folder 5)
      - Conference version, Aug (Box 50, Folder 6)
      - Revised versions, Sep (Box 50, Folder 7-8)
    - Drafts and notes (Box 50, Folder 9-11)
  - "Gender, Social Support and Participation in Protest Movements," Eastern Sociological Society 56th Annual Meeting, 4 Apr 1986 (Box 50)
    - Typescript (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Drafts and notes (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - Statement on New Jersey's proposed welfare reform initiative before the Essex County Human Services Council and Essex County Division on Welfare, 7 Nov 1986 (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Speech to League of Women Voters, 29 Apr 1987(?) (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - "Women in the Pol. Arena," Sociology Department, Rutgers University, 1987 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - "Cooperation and Conflict Among Women in the Welfare Rights Movement," National Women's Studies Association, 23 Jun 1988 (Box 51)
    - Typescripts, Jun and Jul (Box 51, Folder 2-4)
    - Notes (Box 51)
      - General (Box 51, Folder 5)
      - on interviews (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - "Women Activists in the North: The Case of the Metuchen-Edison Race Relations Council," Conference: Women and Civil Rights Movement: Trailblazers and Torchbearers, 1941-1965, Atlanta, GA, Oct 1988 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - "Women in the Civil Rights and Welfare Rights Movement: Reform or Revolution?" Women and Revolution: Thinking About Women Seminar Series, Rutgers University, 2 Feb 1989 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - "Feminist Transformations of Political Theory: 'The Iron Law of Patriarchy' in Social Protest," National Women's Studies Association Convention, Jan 1989 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - "Women and Men and the Welfare Rights Movement," Center for American Women and Politics, 20 Feb 1989 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - "En/Gendering Social Protest: A Women-Centered Perspective," with Rhoda Lois Blumberg, American Sociological Association, Aug 1989 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Testimony on the Welfare Reform and Begin Program, Committee on General Welfare of the City Council of New York, 9 Mar 1990 (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - "Welfare Rights Support Committee," at '"Rising Up Angry:' The Growing Struggle of the Organized Poor" CUNY Law School, 10 Mar 1989 (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - The Family Support Act, Jobs For Youth, 13 Mar 1990 (Box 51, Folder 14)
  - "A Historical View of Welfare Reform: 1930s-1990s," Conference: Charting a New Course: Progressive Policies for New York City, 24 Mar 1990 (Box 51, Folder 15)
  - "The National Welfare Rights Movement: The Social Protest of Poor Women," Hunter College School of Social Work (Mimi Abramovitz's class), 24 Apr 1990 (Box 51, Folder 16)
  - Fourth International Interdisciplinary Congress on Women, Jun 1990 proposal only? (Box 51, Folder 17)
  - Comments on Panel "Reclaiming Feminist Politics: Women's Community Activism, Twentieth Century," Eighth Berkshire Conference on the History of Women, 9 Jun 1990 (Box 51, Folder 18)
  - History of the Welfare Rights Movement, National Welfare Rights Union, 27 Oct 1990 (Box 51, Folder 19)
  - Women and Welfare Reform, National Displaced Homemakers Network Region II Annual Conference, 14 Nov 1991 (Box 51, Folder 20)
  - Welfare reform, District Council 1707 of American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees, 18 Mar 1992 (Box 51, Folder 21)
  - "Workfare in New York State," testimony at the Joint Hearing of the Senate Committee on Social Services and the Senate Committee on Cities, 16 Oct 1992 (Box 51, Folder 22)
  - "Creating a Just and Humane Public Assistance System," testimony before the public hearing of the Puerto Rican/Hispanic Task Forces and State Senator Pedro Espada, Jr., 18 Mar 1994 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - "Welfare Reform in the 1990s: What Women Can Expect and Why," Barnard College Form: The Scholar and the Feminist XX, 23 Apr 1994 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - "The Welfare Rights Movement and Understanding Welfare Reform," Ohio Welfare Rights Organization, 3 Nov 1994 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - National Organization for Women Legal Defense and Education Fund, 3 Mar 1995 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - "The National Welfare Rights Movement," Welfare Rights Initiative Community Leadership Seminar, 19 Sep 1995 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - My Story, Scarsdale Congregational Church, 14 Nov 1995 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - "The National Welfare Rights Movement," Welfare Rights Initiative Community Leadership Seminar, 24 Sep 1996 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - "Welfare Advocacy and Welfare 'Reform,'" Social Action Network Fifth Annual Teach-In, 7 Apr 1997 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - "The National Welfare Rights Movement: Social Protest of Poor Women," Ruth Brandwein's class, SUNY-Stony Brook School of Social Work, 29 Apr 1997 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - "Partnerships for Welfare Reform: The Welfare Reform Network of New York City," Institute for Women's Policy Research, Jul 1997 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - "The National Welfare Rights Movement," Welfare Rights Initiative Community Leadership Seminar, 16 Sep 1997 (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - My experience as an activist, East Hampton Presbyterian Women's Group, 16 Apr 1999 (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - The National Welfare Rights Movement, Hunter College, 14 Sep 1999 (Box 52, Folder 13)
  - "The National Welfare Rights Movement," Welfare Rights Initiative Community Leadership Seminar, 26 Sep 2000 (Box 52, Folder 14)
  - "The National Welfare Rights Movement," Welfare Rights Initiative Community Leadership Seminar, 25 Sep 2001 (Box 52, Folder 15)
  - "Women Organizers Make History" session, Lessons Across the Generations: A Conference For Women Organizers and Activists, Education Center for Community Organizing, Hunter College School of Social Work, 1-2 May 2003 (Box 52, Folder 16)
  - "The Plight of the Welfare Client," undated (Box 52, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1972, 1990-99 (Box 52, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 52)
    - General, 1970, 1988 (Box 52, Folder 19)
    - Notes, 1969-97, undated (Box 52, Folder 20)
    - "Feminist perspective on social protest, ex. WRts Movement," 1988-1992 (Box 52, Folder 21)
- SERIES VIII. WRITINGS
  - "Coalitions in the Welfare Rights Movement: Local Level: Newark, N.J.," Nov 1972 paper for Joseph Conforti course, Rutgers, University (Box 52)
    - Draft (Box 52, Folder 22)
    - Typescript (Box 52, Folder 23)
  - "Cooperation and Conflict among Women in the Welfare Rights Movement," in Bridges of Power: Women's Multicultural Alliances edited by Albrecht and Brewer, 1990 (Box 52, Folder 24)
  - "The Legacy of Welfare Rights," unfinished, 1988 (Box 52, Folder 25)
  - "The National Welfare Rights Movement: Social Protest of Welfare Women (1966-1976)," PhD thesis, Department of Sociology, Rutgers University, 1978 (Box 52)
    - General and proposal, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Typescript (Box 53, Folder 2-15)
    - Interview notes (Box 53)
    - [see also SERIES V. INDIVIDUALS] (Box 53)
      - General, 1972-74, undated (Box 53, Folder 16)
      - Newark WRO/FWRO (Box 53)
        - Notebook [#1], 1971 (Box 54, Folder 1)
        - Notebook 2, 1971-72 (Box 54, Folder 2)
      - Nannette Adams, Shirley Lacy, and Gladys Thomas, Newark WRO and SEDFRE, 27 Dec 1971 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Notes (Box 54)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 54, Folder 4)
      - "Notes for dissertation research," notebook, undated (Box 54, Folder 5)
      - "Always on Sunday" radio program re: George Wiley: transcript and notes, 8 Aug 1973 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - The National Welfare Rights Movement: The Social Protest of Poor Women, Praeger Publishers, 1981 (Box 54)
    - Book (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - General and reviews, 1981-84 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1978-81 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Notes and misc, 1978-79 (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Royalty statements, 1982-84 (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Inquiries re. republication, 1996, 2000 (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - "A Twin-Track Coalition: The National Welfare Rights Organization and the Friends of Welfare Rights," Jan 1972 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - "Twin-Track Coalitions," Jul 1971 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - "Twin-Track Coalitions: A Case Study of the Newark Welfare Rights Organization," course paper for Sociology 621, Joseph Conforti, fall 1971: proposal and notes (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - "Twin-Track Coalitions: A Case Study-Urban WRO/FWRO," [Newark] fall 1972 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - "Twin-Track Coalitions: A Case Study: WRO/FWRO in a Suburban Setting," An observation for Dr. Nelson, Nov 1971 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - "Twin-Track Coalitions: A New Approach in Black-White Coalitions," course paper for Dr. Nelson, fall 1971 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - "Twin Track Coalitions in the Black Power Movement," in Interracial Bonds, 1979 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - "Welfare Rights Leaders in a Becalmed Movement"/"Protest Leadership Outcomes: Welfare Rights Leaders a Decade Later" [research project/proposed book] (Box 55)
    - Correspondence, 1982-87 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Research proposals, 1983-84, undated (Box 55, Folder 9-14)
    - Research grants, 1982-84, undated (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Research budget, 1983 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Potential publishers: notes and correspondence, 1983-84, undated (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Drafts (Box 56)
      - Book summary and contents, 1984 (Box 56, Folder 4)
      - Package sent to publishers, 1983-84 (Box 56, Folder 5)
      - Package compiled after contract with Praeger Publishers, 1985 (Box 56, Folder 6)
      - 1984-85 (Box 56, Folder 7-8)
    - Interviews, 1983-84 (Box 56)
    - [see also SERIES V. INDIVIDUALS for correspondence and transcripts] (Box 56)
      - Potential interviews (Box 56)
        - Lists and notes (Box 56, Folder 9)
        - Card file (Box 56, Folder 10-12)
      - Correspondence (Box 56)
        - No answers (Box 56, Folder 13)
        - Not located (Box 56, Folder 14)
      - Sampling frame (Box 56, Folder 15)
      - Completed interviews: lists and general notes (Box 56, Folder 16-18)
      - Interview notes/notebooks (Box 56)
        - Maud Davis (Box 56, Folder 19)
        - Bert DeLeeuw (Box 56, Folder 20)
        - Book #5: Marian Kramer, Detroit, 16 Apr 1984 (Box 56, Folder 21)
        - Pauline London, Philadelphia, 24 Jul 1984 (Box 56, Folder 22)
        - Bobbie McMahon, Sarah McPherson (Box 57, Folder 1)
        - Elizabeth Perry (Box 57, Folder 2)
        - Jeannette Washington, 1 Jun 1984 (Box 57, Folder 3)
        - Funicello, Hamer, Evans, Willis, and Myles (Box 57, Folder 4)
        - Evans, Rowe, Kydd, and J. Williams (Box 57, Folder 5)
        - Duncan, Linton, and Davis (Box 57, Folder 6)
        - Book #3, Atlanta: Matthews (cont'd), Dandridge, Lee, Watley, Serrano, and Willis, Apr 1984 (Box 57, Folder 7)
        - #1 Trip, Book #1: Tillmon, Johnson, Sampson, Henry, Palladino, Rathke, Saulsberry, Nelson, Wooford (Box 57, Folder 8)
        - Book #2: Jackson, Jermany, B. Thomas, Smart, Williams (cont'd), Matthews (Box 57, Folder 9)
        - Brown, McNeil, Hal, Stevens, Hurley, Glynn, Jun 1984 (Box 57, Folder 10)
        - Jeter and Jones (cont'd) (Box 57, Folder 11)
        - Book #4: Columbus and Detroit: B. Young, Smith, Snyder, Peck, Willis "not taped? just notes" (Box 57, Folder 12)
        - Pastereich, Grant, and James, 20 Jun 1984 (Box 57, Folder 13)
      - Interview guide (Box 57)
        - Drafts (Box 57, Folder 14-15)
        - Research (Box 57, Folder 16)
      - Research trips (Box 57)
        - General notes (Box 57, Folder 17)
        - 1984 Calendar (Box 57, Folder 18)
        - Apr 1984 trip notes (Box 58, Folder 1)
        - Summer 1984 trip notes (Box 58, Folder 2)
      - Data analysis (Box 58)
        - General notes (Box 58, Folder 3-4)
        - Coding scheme: notes and drafts (Box 58, Folder 5-9)
    - Poor women's views of President Carter's Welfare Reform Proposal "Better Jobs and Income Program" (Box 58)
      - Transcript of testimony, Sep-Nov 1977 (Box 58, Folder 10)
      - Notes (Box 58, Folder 11-12)
    - Notes, general (Box 58)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 58, Folder 13-14)
      - Bibliography (Box 58, Folder 15)
      - Conclusion (Box 58, Folder 16-17)
      - Conclusion (cont'd) (Box 59, Folder 1-2)
      - Introduction (Box 59, Folder 3)
      - Leaders (Box 59)
        - Off track (Box 59, Folder 4)
        - On track (Box 59, Folder 5)
        - Side-tracked (Box 59, Folder 6)
        - Switched track (Box 59, Folder 7)
      - Method (Box 59, Folder 8-9)
      - My hypothesis/theory (Box 59, Folder 10)
      - Preface (Box 59, Folder 11)
      - Theoretical questions (Box 59, Folder 12)
      - Wording (Box 59, Folder 13)
    - Notes on theory (Box 59)
      - Class (Box 59, Folder 14)
      - Leadership (Box 59, Folder 15)
      - Political activism (Box 59)
        - General/origins (Box 59, Folder 16)
        - Age/generational cohort (Box 59, Folder 17)
        - Changes/contradictions (Box 59, Folder 18)
        - Education (Box 59, Folder 19)
        - Family (Box 59, Folder 20)
        - Health (Box 59, Folder 21)
        - Power (Box 59, Folder 22)
      - Political behavior (Box 59)
        - General (Box 60, Folder 1)
        - Participation (Box 60, Folder 2)
        - Race (Box 60, Folder 3)
        - Theory and evidence (Box 60, Folder 4)
        - Time 1 (Box 60, Folder 5)
      - Political behavior (cont'd) (Box 60)
        - Time 2 (Box 60, Folder 6)
        - Time 3 (Box 60, Folder 7)
      - Political ideology (Box 60)
        - General (Box 60, Folder 8)
        - Political attitudes/orientation toward protest (Box 60, Folder 9)
      - Political integration (Box 60, Folder 10)
      - Political outcomes (Box 60, Folder 11)
      - Political socialization (Box 60, Folder 12)
      - Social control (Box 60, Folder 13)
      - Social supports (Box 60, Folder 14-15)
      - Studies (Box 60)
        - Blumberg and Goldstein, 1976-82 (Box 61, Folder 1)
        - Casenave and Leon, 1985 (Box 61, Folder 2)
        - Orum et al, 1974 (Box 61, Folder 3)
        - Pizzorno, undated (Box 61, Folder 4)
        - Braungart and Braungart, 1980, 1984-85 (Box 61, Folder 5-7)
        - Foner, 1974 (Box 61, Folder 8)
        - Whalen and Flacks, 1980 (Box 61, Folder 9)
        - Thompson, 1971 (Box 61, Folder 10)
        - Isaac et al, 1980 (Box 61, Folder 11)
        - Demerath, 1971 (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - Women and Social Protest edited by Guida West and Rhoda Lois Blumberg, 1990 (Box 61)
    - Correspondence, 1985-91 (Box 61, Folder 13)
    - Reviews, 1992-93 (Box 61, Folder 14)
    - Resources (Box 61)
      - General and miscellaneous (Box 61, Folder 15-17)
      - Economic justice (Box 61, Folder 18)
      - Environmental movement (Box 61, Folder 19)
      - International (Box 61)
        - General (Box 61, Folder 20)
        - Africa (Box 62, Folder 1)
        - Latin America (Box 62, Folder 2)
        - Middle East (Box 62, Folder 3)
        - Miscellaneous countries (Box 62, Folder 4)
      - Labor movement (Box 62, Folder 5)
      - Peace/disarmament (Box 62, Folder 6)
      - United States (Box 62)
        - African-American women (Box 62, Folder 7)
        - Civil Rights movement (Box 62, Folder 8)
        - Conservative women (Box 62, Folder 9)
        - Hispanas (Box 62, Folder 10)
        - Women of color (Box 62, Folder 11)
        - Women's movement: March for Women's Equality/Women's Lives, 2004 (Box 62, Folder 12)
      - Violence (Box 62, Folder 13)
  - "Women in the Welfare Rights Movement: Reform or Revolution?" Dialectical Anthropology 15: 141-149, 1990 (Box 62, Folder 14)
  - "Workfare is Unfair," Georgetown Journal on Fighting Poverty, Vol. 1 No. 1, 1993 (Box 62, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous, 1972-96 (Box 62, Folder 16)
- SERIES IX. SUBJECT FILES
  - Abortion (Box 62)
    - General, 1969-80, undated (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - New Jersey, 1974-80, n.d (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Adequate income (Box 63)
    - General, 1979-2002, n.d (Box 63, Folder 3-6)
    - Clippings, 2000 (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - Affirmative action (Box 63)
    - General, 1975-76 (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - Clippings, 1975 (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - Aging, 1974-85, undated (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Birth control, undated (Box 63, Folder 11)
  - Blacks (Box 63)
    - General, 1965-79, 1992-95, undated (Box 63, Folder 12-13)
    - Clippings, 1971-2005 (Box 63, Folder 14)
    - Women, 1968-76, 1992, undated (Box 63, Folder 15)
    - Socialism, undated (Box 63, Folder 16)
    - Solidarity, 1970-78, undated (Box 63, Folder 17)
    - Sources of racial problems, 1975, undated (Box 63, Folder 18)
  - Child care, 1972, 1997-2002, undated (Box 64, Folder 1-2)
  - Child support, 1992, 2000 (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Children, 1972-99 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Church (Box 64)
    - General, 1962-2002, undated (Box 64, Folder 5-8)
    - Catholic, 1969-79 (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - Jewish, 1967-74, .n.d. (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - Methodist, 1965 (Box 64, Folder 11)
    - Religious involvement, 1961-85, n.d (Box 64, Folder 12)
  - Coalitions, 1971-75, undated (Box 64, Folder 13)
  - Competing movements (Box 64)
    - General, 1970-75, undated (Box 64, Folder 14)
    - Environment, 1970-74, undated (Box 64, Folder 15)
    - Labor, 1971-77 (Box 64, Folder 16)
  - Displaced homemakers, 1975-90, undated (Box 65, Folder 1-2)
  - Domestic violence (Box 65)
    - General, 1993-2001, undated (Box 65, Folder 3-7)
    - Prostitution, 2001-02 (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - Economic security, 1966-2002 (Box 66)
  - Economy, 1975-2001, undated (Box 66)
  - Education and training, 1976-2006, undated (Box 66)
  - Family, 1976-2003, undated (Box 67, Folder 1-3)
  - Fatherhood, 1970-2001, undated (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Food/hunger, 1968-2003, undated (Box 67, Folder 5-8)
  - Farm subsidies, 1935, 36, 1969-73, undated (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - Health (Box 67)
    - General, 1971, 2001-04, undated (Box 67, Folder 10)
    - Disabilities, 2001 (Box 67, Folder 11)
  - Housing (Box 67, Folder 5-6)
    - 1973-99 (Box 67)
    - 2000-05, undated (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Household employment, 1970-71, undated (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Immigration, 1969-2001, undated (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Individual, 1967-78 (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Intellectuals, 1973-75, undated (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Judiciary (Box 68)
    - General, 1971-72 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Supreme Court, 1963-2005, undated (Box 68, Folder 7-12)
    - Failure of "Right to Welfare," 1965, 1972-74 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Labor, 1966-76, undated (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Legal services (Box 69)
    - General, 1969-73, 1983, 2001, undated (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Clippings, 1970-83 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Rights, 1964, 1970-73, undated (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - Media (Box 69)
    - General, 1968-76, undated (Box 69, Folder 6-7)
    - New York Times Index, 1966, 68, 71, 73 (Box 69, Folder 8)
  - Networking, 1971-84, undated (Box 69, Folder 9-10)
  - New Jersey (Box 69)
    - General, 1964-80, undated (Box 70, Folder 1-3)
    - Division on Civil Rights, 1965-68 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Welfare (Box 70)
      - General, 1967-78, undated (Box 70, Folder 5)
      - Statistics, 1978 (Box 70, Folder 6)
      - Division of Public Welfare (Box 70)
        - General, 1966-67 (Box 70, Folder 7)
        - "Narrative Report of the Expanded Study of Assistance Standards and Allowances in the ADC Program," 1972 (Box 70, Folder 8)
        - "Public Assistance Manual," 1974-78 (Box 70, Folder 9-11)
    - Governor's Select Commission on Civil Disorders, 1967-71 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Governor's Task Force on Welfare Management, 1966-71 (Box 71, Folder 2-4)
    - Governor's Welfare Study Commission, 1971 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Welfare Rehabilitation Institute, 1971 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Montclair, 1967-74, undated (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - New Jersey Graduated Work Incentive Experiment, 1973 (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Newark, 1966-68, 71-72, 78, undated (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Plainfield, 1964-65, undated (Box 71, Folder 10)
  - New York, 1968-2001 (Box 72, Folder 1-2)
  - Philanthropy, 1980, 2000-01 (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - Political activism (Box 72)
    - General, 1971-77 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Consequences, undated (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Economics, 1982-86, undated (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Religion, 1973-86 (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - Political climate (Box 72)
    - General, 1964-2001, undated (Box 72, Folder 8-9)
    - Heritage Foundation, undated (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - The Right, 1972-96 (Box 72, Folder 11)
    - Sociopolitical climate, 1975-80, undated (Box 72, Folder 12)
  - Poverty (Box 72)
    - General, 1965-2004, undated (Box 73, Folder 1-4)
    - Feminization of poverty, 1972-2001 (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Women and children, 1973-2000, undated (Box 73, Folder 6-7)
  - Racism, 1975, 1989 (Box 73, Folder 8)
  - Social support (Box 73)
    - 1971-87 (Box 73, Folder 9-10)
    - undated (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Taxes, 1969-2001, undated (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - Unemployment insurance, 1971-2002, undated (Box 74, Folder 3-5)
  - United States Government (Box 74)
    - General, 1969-2001, undated (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare: publications, 1964-75 (Box 74, Folder 7-8)
    - Department of Labor, "Employment Opportunities Pilot Program: Welfare Reform Demonstration," 1978 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Legislation (Box 75)
      - 1935-75 (Box 75, Folder 2-13)
      - 1977-97 (Box 76, Folder 1-6)
    - Reagan budget, 1983, undated (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - Urban crisis, 1968-80, n..d (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - Welfare (Box 76)
    - General, 1965-69 (Box 76, Folder 9-10)
    - General, 1970-2006, undated (Box 77, Folder 1-9)
    - Clippings, 1967-2004, undated (Box 77, Folder 10-12)
    - Aid to Families with Dependent Children (AFDC), 1975-76, 1992, undated (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - "The Anatomy of Welfare," ABC News transcript, 14 Apr 1971 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Children, 2001 (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Data, 1969-90 (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Earned Income Tax Credit, 2000-01, undated (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Education, 1989-2005, undated (Box 78, Folder 6-9)
    - Food stamps, 1974, 1983 (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - Guaranteed income/income maintenance (Box 78)
      - General, 1967-74, undated (Box 78, Folder 11)
      - President's Commission on Income Maintenance Programs (Box 78)
        - General, 1968-69 (Box 78, Folder 12)
        - Final report, Nov 1969 (Box 78, Folder 13-15)
    - International (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Leavers, 1998-2004 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Mothers, 1991-95, undated (Box 79, Folder 3)